<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-14T16:00:24+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Maya Engel - Music and Sound</title><subtitle>Music and Sound Design for Games and other media</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Metempsychosis - GWJ#17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/01/metempsychosis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metempsychosis - GWJ#17" /><published>2020-05-01T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/01/metempsychosis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/01/metempsychosis.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/metempsychosis.png&quot; alt=&quot;Metempsychosis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the 17th Godot Wild Jam we made what I can only describe as a “turn based co-op escape room like adventure game”.
You play together with a friend, either online, or on the same device. You’re stuck in a space ship, and you’re trying to find the way out together. The catch is that you are never playing together, and you don’t know what the other’s layout is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted the soundtrack to be mysterious, quiet, and eerie. At first, I went with a mostly orchestral track. A few days into the jam, I realized it was not right. I started messing around with more layered synthesizers sound, with very minimal melodic lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a time limit for each player of 5 minutes. When there’s around 1 minute left, a heavy bass layer comes in, signifying the end.
On top of that, whenever you enter a terminal, a low pass filter goes over the music, to signify focus. It is also intended to make room for the sound effects that play in the sound puzzle terminal. I wrote the dynamic layering and lowpass trigger myself in GDScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can play the game here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://animerrill.itch.io/metempsychosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://animerrill.itch.io/metempsychosis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/metempsychosis.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/metem_code.png&quot; alt=&quot;Custom layering code in GDSCript&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jigoku</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/jigoku.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jigoku" /><published>2020-04-30T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/jigoku</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/jigoku.html">&lt;p&gt;In the game, you play as Rin, a former Senshi (Demon Hunter). In the quest to get revenge, demons from one of the 16 hells, kill Rin’s wife and take her soul to the Hanu hell. Rin makes his way toward and through the hell in his quest to find and save her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote score that’s a hybrid between Japanese music and my own western style. I incorporated both ethnic instruments, electronic sounds, and western orchestral instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The track below was made using a sampled shakuhachi flute I performed myself. I used a Max MSP patch that imitates tape looping. I performed over my own playing multiple times to create a drone like sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/jigoku.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://smallstudios2020.itch.io/jigoku&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In the game, you play as Rin, a former Senshi (Demon Hunter). In the quest to get revenge, demons from one of the 16 hells, kill Rin’s wife and take her soul to the Hanu hell. Rin makes his way toward and through the hell in his quest to find and save her.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dream Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dream Again" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dream_again.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dream Again&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:350px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an interactive narrative design seminar, we made a short game about a struggling artist who has nightmares about his abusive boss. This game was made in 10 days.
As you can see by the thumbnail, it’s a very dark and moody game. Yet, there are short daylight sections. Contrast was vital. The forests and eerie colours immediately sparked drony synth sounds in me. I layered a lot of different sounds over each other, mostly just playing one note, fading in and out. I wanted to create a constant sense of dread in the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main theme uses a piano. To create a connection between the main theme, which plays during the start of the game, and the dreams, I sampled a pianio and used it as a percussive sound in the dream sections. This added a sense of the world being morphed to the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FG5uCVoaFQM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forest - music for a painting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forest - music for a painting" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/forest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forest&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:350px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of an assignment, I wrote music for a painting. I chose this beautiful painting by Ryuchi Yamashiro. The simplicity of it all immediately struck me. Through the use of a shakuhachi flute, granular synthesis, and FX chains, I wanted to try and evoke the feeling of a quiet forest, with a danger nearing.
All the flute parts have been composed, performed, and recorded by me. It was important for me to use a real flute, as opposed to a virtual one, so I could get very strong experession into the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/forest.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Space Squids: Race in Space</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Space Squids: Race in Space" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/space_squids_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Squids&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was made during the Global Game Jam 2020. The theme was “repair”.
We madea goofy racing game for 4 players. The goal is to dash your way around the course as fast as possible. Whenever you dash, you lose a tentacle. The catch is that you can pick up other squids’ and your own tentacles to get more boosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game screams fun, goofiness, and silly. I spent the first evening sketching a melody, and eventually settled on one. I decided to make a synthy upbeat track, with some nice percussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/space_squids.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cosmic S.N.A.F.U.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/cosmic-snafu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cosmic S.N.A.F.U." /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/cosmic-snafu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/cosmic-snafu.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cosmic_snafu.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cosmic S.N.A.F.U.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Cosmic S.N.A.F.U., you must survive for as long as possible as your ship moves uncontrollably through an asteroid field. Your ship’s power must be maintained to keep your shields and weapons online, and you must keep the radio in-tune to keep your radar working. And woe betide if your partner thinks you’re ignoring them…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was made during the 2020 Gamemaker’s Toolkist Game Jam. 
The music system consists of a main loop, the bass and drums with a melody that plays while you’re in the cockpit view.
Whenevever you open one of your screens, a new melody will play and a lowpass filter is added to the main loop.
Additionally, the music as a whole speeds up as things get more intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can play the game at https://johngabrieluk.itch.io/cosmic-snafu&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Piano Etude in Purr Data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/28/random_piano_etude.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Piano Etude in Purr Data" /><published>2020-04-28T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/28/random_piano_etude</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/28/random_piano_etude.html">&lt;p&gt;As part of a university assignment, I wrote a Purr Data patch using random pitched, picked from the octatonic scale, and random rhythms.
This patch has a list of pitches and rhythms.
The slider in the video indicates the range in which the list gets read. So the higher the value, the higher the amount of pitches and rhythms you the patch can pick from. Thus the slider controls the amount of randomness in the composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding:75% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/423554211&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:75%;height:75%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/423554211&quot;&gt;Generative Piano Etude&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user114311096&quot;&gt;Maya Composer&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As part of a university assignment, I wrote a Purr Data patch using random pitched, picked from the octatonic scale, and random rhythms. This patch has a list of pitches and rhythms. The slider in the video indicates the range in which the list gets read. So the higher the value, the higher the amount of pitches and rhythms you the patch can pick from. Thus the slider controls the amount of randomness in the composition.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Growth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/growth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Growth" /><published>2019-12-01T19:22:59+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T19:22:59+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/growth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/growth.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/growth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Growth&quot; style=&quot;width:25%;height:25%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growth is a co-op game in which two players take control of a brother and sister. The two children have to make their way away from climate change, in search of a new place to live. 
The game is centered gender roles in society, and how they can change. Throughout this story, the brother and sister will break the social expectations other people have of them. Together they become their own person through a story of loss, change, and hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to emphasize the two different characters, so both the brother and sister have their own instrument and leitmotif. The sister has the erhu, and the brother has a flute.
Throughout the game, the instruments take over the melody depending on who’s in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/growth_1.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journey in F</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/journey.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journey in F" /><published>2019-12-01T19:22:59+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T19:22:59+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/12/01/journey.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/journey.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Trio Burlesco&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I participated in the Princess Christina Concours. Here I wrote a composition for the Trio Burlesco ensemble, consisting of clarinet, piano, cello, and xylophone. It was a wonderful opportunity and certainly sparked my ever growing love for writing for live players. The piece is about journeying to a place, and overcoming danger and obstacles in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/journey.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>