<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-06T22:08:08+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Maya Engel - Music and Sound</title><subtitle>Music and Sound Design for Games and other media</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Metempsychosis - Godot Wild Jam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/metempsychosis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metempsychosis - Godot Wild Jam " /><published>2020-04-30T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/metempsychosis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/30/metempsychosis.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/metempsychosis.png&quot; alt=&quot;Metempsychosis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the 17th Godot Wild Jam we made what I can only describe as a “turn based co-op escape room like adventure game”.
You play together with a friend, either online, or on the same device. You’re stuck in a space ship, and you’re trying to find the way out together. The catch is that you are never playing together, and you don’t know what the other’s layout is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted the soundtrack to be mysterious, quiet, and eerie. At first, I went with a mostly orchestral track. A few days into the jam, I realized it was not right. I started messing around with more layered synthesizers sound, with very minimal melodic lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a time limit for each player of 5 minutes. When there’s around 1 minute left, a heavy bass layer comes in, signifying the end.
On top of that, whenever you enter a terminal, a low pass filter goes over the music, to signify focus. It is also intended to make room for the sound effects that play in the sound puzzle terminal. I wrote the dynamic layering and lowpass trigger myself in GDScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/metempsychosis.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/metem_code.png&quot; alt=&quot;Custom layering code in GDSCript&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Space Squids: Race in Space</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Space Squids: Race in Space" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/space-squids.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/space_squids_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Space Squids&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was made during the Global Game Jam 2020. The theme was “repair”.
We madea goofy racing game for 4 players. The goal is to dash your way around the course as fast as possible. Whenever you dash, you lose a tentacle. The catch is that you can pick up other squids’ and your own tentacles to get more boosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game screams fun, goofiness, and silly. I spent the first evening sketching a melody, and eventually settled on one. I decided to make a synthy upbeat track, with some nice percussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/space_squids.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forest - music for a painting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forest - music for a painting" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/forest.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/forest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Forest&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;height:350px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of an assignment, I wrote music for a painting. I chose this beautiful painting by Ryuchi Yamashiro. The simplicity of it all immediately struck me. Through the use of a shakuhachi flute, granular synthesis, and FX chains, I wanted to try and evoke the feeling of a quiet forest, with a danger nearing.
All the flute parts have been composed, performed, and recorded by me. It was important for me to use a real flute, as opposed to a virtual one, so I could get very strong experession into the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/forest.wav&quot; type=&quot;audio/wav&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dream Again</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dream Again" /><published>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T20:22:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/04/29/dream-again.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dream_again.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dream Again&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an interactive narrative design seminar, we made a short game about a struggling artist who has nightmares about his abusive boss. This game was made in 10 days.
As you can see by the thumbnail, it’s a very dark and moody game. Yet, there are short daylight sections. Contrast was vital. The forests and eerie colours immediately sparked drony synth sounds in me. I layered a lot of different sounds over each other, mostly just playing one note, fading in and out. I wanted to create a constant sense of dread in the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main theme uses a piano. To create a connection between the main theme, which plays during the start of the game, and the dreams, I sampled a pianio and used it as a percussive sound in the dream sections. This added a sense of the world being morphed to the music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FG5uCVoaFQM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>